Bibiana Mollinedo Rivadeneira

Córdoba, Argentina (disposed to relocate)
+54 9 358 5044557
brivadeneira@protonmail.com
qithub.com/brivadeneira
linkedin.com/in/bibianarivadeneira

Python Developer with +4 years of hands-on experience and a **Telecommunications** degree. Open source/Free Software enthusiastic. +4 years teaching computing. Volunteer/organizer of tech events such as FLISoL, Django Girls, TEDx. Hackathon mentions/prizes in the NASA SpaceApps event, and IT challenges with social focus. Strongly interested in networking, RTC software, space mission projects.

EXPERIENCE

Properati/OLX (Argentina), Backend Developer — April 2021-Present

Argentinian real state startUp that operates an online marketplace for lodging and sale of properties

Collaboration in the development of a new microservices architecture for buyers and sellers platforms depart from a Ruby monolith.

Tech stack: Go, Python, Elasticsearch, Google Cloud, Gitflow, Agile, JIRA.

<u>Senpai Academy</u> (Uruguay), Python teacher — October 2021-Present

Ed academy

- Prepared +10 jupyter notebooks for teaching.
- +40hs Python fundamentals teaching

Tech stack: Python, Jupyterlab, draw.io

Sadosky Foundation (Argentina), Technical Coordinator / Remote Computational Thinking teacher — Aug 2019-Present

The first Computational Thinking program in Argentina / Primary school remote classes in "Plan Ceibal" - Uruguay

- Implemented several group dynamics, modern project management staff and teaching resources to empower +15 mentors.
- Gave +500 lessons and collected data about more +10 success stories.
- Made funny classes to inspire +400 kids in computing with Scratch and micro:bit.

Welo.tv (Argentina), Python Developer — Jan - April 2021

RTMP and HTTP multimedia streaming on demand written in Python.

- Promoted standards and best practices in the backend team.
- Redesigned and refactored +4 existing projects, improving documentation by adding friendly diagrams.

Tech stack: Python3, fastAPI, jwplatform, elasticsearch, Gcloud, docker, kubernetes, git, gitlab.

AG Projects (remote-The netherlands), Python Developer — Jan-Dec 2020

Real time communication open source software written in Python.

- Rewrited and packaging +5 twisted projects by Python/Cython 2 to 3 migration with modern stack.
- Developed a Mobile push notifications RTC server from scratch supplying an easier way to audit problems related to the processing of those notifications with fastAPI.

Engineering School at National University of Río Cuarto (Argentina), Teacher assistant Nov 2016-Feb 2020

"Introduction to Telecommunications Engineering" course

- Prepared +4 <u>laboratory experiences</u>, +10 technical notes.
- By teaching and promoting empowering activities to +500 first year students.

Fonexa S.A. (Argentina), IoT Telecommunications Internship — Aug-Dic 2019

LoRa/LoRaWAN IoT prototype solution to the professional internship

- Quality academic research about +50 telecommunications fundamentals and +20 own diagrams.
- Built a cheap but powerful prototype using Arduino, ESP32, Raspberry Pi with +3 potential case of local industry use.

Self-employed (Argentina), Python Instructor — May 2019-Dic 2019

- Organized and mentored general purpose, on demand and scientific Python courses to +100 assistants.
- Managed scholarships for +10 girls and drove a local python community.

Freelance (Argentina), Python web developer — 2018

• Developed a REST API and data visualization dashboard for Freeradius for +50 users using Python3, Flask, SQLite, Dash.

PROJECTS

I love pdf telegram bot – 2021

(Personal Project) A Telegram bot which offers all ilovepdf.com features using Python3 and telegram-bot lib.

ARQcheros - 2018

(Academic project) Flask web application to admin, manage and automate calculus of archaeological data.

EspectroAR - 2017

(Introduction to Telecommunications course) Data visualization of Argentinian radio Spectrum with HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, Scratch, Markdown: advanced; Golang, Bash, Latex, intermediate; Ruby, HTML, CSS, JS: fundamental Frameworks and Tools: FastAPI, advanced; Flask, Jekyll, twisted, Django: intermediate; docker, fundamental

Languages: English, Intermediate; Spanish, Native

EDUCATION

National University of Río Cuarto – Río Cuarto, Córdoba, Argentina.

Bachelor of Engineering, Telecommunications Engineering, —Feb 2012-Dic 2019

Signal analysis and processing, networking and optical communication fundamentals, engineer simulations.

National University of Jujuy - San Salvador de Jujuy, Jujuy, Argentina.

Secondary diploma, IT Technician, —Feb 2006 - March 2012

Algorithm fundamentals, OOP.